

PROFILE

I am a full stack developer from Fort Mill South Carolina. I develop websites using frameworks such as Vue and React. I have experience working as a solo contractor for a local business and as a member of a team of a nationwide staffing company. I am graduating from BYUI in April 2024 with a bachelor's degree in software engineering and a certificate in Web Development. In my free time I enjoy mountain unicycling with my friends and camping in Lynnville NC. You can view my website below to see the various projects that I have worked on.

CONTACT

PHONE: (803)-504-2034

EMAIL:

skylerjsimpson@gmail.com

WEBSITE:

skylersimpson.netlify.app



SKYLER SIMPSON

Full Stack Web Developer

EDUCATION

Brigham Young University Idaho 2020-2024

BS, Software Engineering, Certified in Web Development

SCHOOL EXPERIENCE

Web Development:

I have found a love for web development and chose to focus my studies on it. I took many classes focused on Frontend development, backend development, Full stack, web design, and advanced CSS.

Front-End:

I gained experience in frameworks such as react and Vue. I made my own custom components to solve complex problems. I worked with tools such as Netlify, Heroku, and Vercel for deployment. I explored options for styling such as CSS, SCSS, and Tailwind.

Back-End:

I have worked extensively with node. I became proficient at deploying RESTful APIs that used both SQL and noSQL databases. I took particular interest in ORM tools such as sequelize and prisma for managing relational databases. I used various hosting services and database tools such as render, MongoDB, AWS, pgAdmin, and mySQL,

WORK EXPERIENCE

Stone Crest Suites: Web Full Stack Developer Aug 2023-Jan 2024

- Developed a full stack webpage that allowed users to reserve office space.
- Implemented director privileges, allowing directors to customize the entire website and edit the data in any way they need.

OnDiem Dental Staffing: Front End Developer Jan 2024–PRESENT

- Contributing to the creation of OnDiems staffing website by developing solutions for a better user experience.
- Using Vue to create new components and update existing components.
- Gaining experience working on a larger development team and working for a company.

SKILLS

HTML CSS JavaScript Frameworks
Node ORMs Figma TailWind
Version Control